<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><data date-time-format="iso8601"><event start="1304-07-20" title="Petrarch born">Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) is born in Arezzo to the notary ser Petracco di Parenzo and lady Eletta Canigiani.</event><event start="1358" title="Itinerarium syriacum">One of Petrarch’s Milanese friends, Giovannolo da Mandello encouraged him to a pilgrimage to the Holy Land: he refuses and in return writes the Itinerarium syriacum in return.</event><event start="1358" title="Emendations to the Secretum">Petrarch contiunes the editing of the &lt;i&gt;Secretum&lt;/i&gt;.</event><event start="1358" title="Padua and Venice">At the end of the year, Petrarch travels to Padova and Venezia where he meets Leonzio Pilato, from whom he hopes to learn Greek.</event><event start="1358-09-12" title="Triumphus Cupidinis">On September 12th 1358, he edited the section of Triumphus Cupidinis in his draft papers now known as Vaticano Latino 3196 (postilla on the lower margin of c.17r).</event><event start="1362" title="Fragmentorum Liber">Giovanni Boccaccio prepares and transcribes his copy of the Fragmentorum Liber, the most ancient complete manuscript survived of the earlier version of the Fragmenta. It is conserved today in the Vatica Library with the collocation: Vaticano Chigiano L V 176.</event><event start="1362-01-04" title="Miscellanea 2: letter to Leonardo Beccanugi">On January 4th from Venice, Petrarch writes a letter to 	Leonardo Beccanugi asking him to help his friend Maestre Anastagio and asks for a loan to buy books in case there is any of interest. This is the only letter that has survived written in volgare. This does not mean, as Feo doubted, that (Pancheri: 367).</event><event start="1362" title="Tennemi Amor anni ventuno ardendo: Rvf 360 [r 364]">“Tennemi Amor anni ventuno ardendo” is one of the so called anniversary poems which celebrates the twenty-first anniversary of the innamoramento which happened, in Petrarch’s words, on January 6th 1327. This sonnet, therefore carries the date of January 6th 1348. This does not necessary mean, though, that it was written on that day, or even in that year.</event><event start="1362-08-28" title="Varia 43: Venice and Petrarch’s library">In September he moves to Venezia. He agrees with the chancellor Benintendi Ravagnani to donate his library to the Republic of Venezia after his own death, in exchange to a residence in “palazzo Molin”, on the Schiavoni shore close to the Ducal Palace (“Varia 43”, Padua August 28).</event><event start="1362-09-11" title="Familiares XXII 1: letter to Pandolfo Malatesta">In Venice on September 11th Petrarch replies to a letter 	received from the signore Pandolfo Malatesta on whether he should 	remarry after the loss of his first wife.</event><event start="1862-10" isDuration="true" end="1862-11" title="Varia 19: Azzo da Correggio’s death">After receiving the news of Azzo da Correggio’s death, between the end of october and the beginning of november he writes a letter to their common friend Moggio da Parma to express his grief for the loss of the signore of virtue who had always valued Petrarch as incomparable among the other poets.</event><event start="1362" title="Varia 4: letter to Modio Parmensi">On November 17th and December 9th in Venice, Petrarch writes a letter to Moggio da Parma in which he recommends him to read his works, especiallt the &lt;i&gt;Vita Solitaria&lt;/i&gt;. If they were transcribed, as he hopes, they should be bound and embellished as they usually are.</event><event start="1373" title="Varia 9: “nugella meas vulgares”">On January 4th, he writes to Pandolfo Malatesta (“Varia 9”) suggesting the intention to send some of his poems. In the same month of January, Pandlofo dies.</event><event start="1873-01" isDuration="true" end="1873-03" title="Invectiva contra eum qui maledixit Italiae">Between January and March, Petrarch writes the &lt;i&gt;Invectiva contra eum qui maledixit Italiae&lt;/i&gt; in reply to Jean de Hesdin.</event><event start="1373" title="Seniles XVII 3 and XVII 2: last letters to Boccaccio">On June 4th in the Colli Euganei he sends a letter to Giovanni Boccaccio with his own translation of the novella “Griselda” from the &lt;i&gt;Decameron&lt;/i&gt; (“Sen.XVII 3”) and on April 28th writes writes him again from Padua one of his last letters stating he will never stop his studies (“Sen.XVII 3”).</event><event start="1373-10-02" title="Orazione in Venice">In September he goes to Venezia with Novello, son of Francesco da Carrara in a mission to bring peace between Venezia and Padova. He pronounces an Orazione on October 2nd.</event><event start="1373" title="Seniles XVI 3: Arquà">Petrarch hopes to return to Arquà before Easter of the same year. He eventually does.</event></data>